appypie.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy policy

**Privacy Policy**

Effective as of April 18, 2019, Appy Pie LLC, Appy Pie Ltd & Appy Pie LLP collectively called (“Appy Pie”) have updated the Privacy Policy.

 **Introduction**

Appy Pie LLC, Appy Pie Ltd & Appy Pie LLP collectively called (“Appy Pie”) operates several websites including appypie.com (the “Websites”), as well as a number of mobile applications on behalf of our customers (collectively, the “Applications”). It is Appy Pie’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our Websites and Applications.

This Policy describes how Appy Pie collects, uses, shares, and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes your choices regarding the use, access, and correction of your personal information.

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Appy Pie we have a few fundamental principles:

We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)

We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights. We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services. In our social networking and mobile application products, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

 **EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield**

Appy Pie complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. Appy Pie has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such information. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List[[1]](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)

Appy Pie is responsible for processing of the personal data it receives under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Appy Pie complies with the Privacy Shield principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to the personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Appy Pie is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities for instance, meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions (described in detail on the Privacy Shield website [[2]](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint) you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

 **Passive Collection**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g. HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

 **Gathering of Personal Information**

Certain visitors to Appy Pie’s Websites and users of Appy Pie’s Applications choose to interact with Appy Pie in ways that require Appy Pie to gather personal information. The amount and type of information that Appy Pie gathers depend on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at www.appypie.com to provide their email address. Those who engage in transactions with Appy Pie – are asked to provide additional information including necessary personal and financial information such as a credit card number for processing the financial transactions. In each case, Appy Pie collects such information only when it is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Appy Pie, for example your name, address and phone number where needed. Appy Pie does not disclose personal information other than as described below, and visitors can always refuse to supply personal information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Website-related and Application-related activities.

We may also collect form you name and email address about your contacts in order to refer our products or services.

Through our import contacts feature we may collect the name, email address, of your contacts in order to let you recommend our services to your contacts who might be interested in creating an app for their business and in the process rewarding both you and your contacts

When you provide us with personal information about your contacts, we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided.

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com).

 **Aggregated Statistics**

Appy Pie may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors on its Websites and users of its Applications. For instance, Appy Pie may monitor the most popular social networks on the appypie.com site & may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Appy Pie does not disclose personal information other than as described below.

 **Sharing of Certain Personal Information**

Appy Pie discloses personal information only to those employees, contractors, service providers and affiliated organizations that (i) need the particular information in order to process it on Appy Pie’s behalf or to provide services available at Appy Pie’s Websites and Applications, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. They are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. These services may include: fulfilling your orders, payment processing, providing customer service, sending marketing communications, fulfilling subscription services, conducting research and analysis, providing cloud computing infrastructure. SMS integration, Cloud printing and more such services.

Some of those employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations may be located outside your home country; by using Appy Pie’s Websites and Applications, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Appy Pie will not rent or sell personal information to anyone. Apart from its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations, as described above, Appy Pie discloses personal information only when required to do so by law, or when Appy Pie believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Appy Pie, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Appy Pie Website or Application and have supplied your email address, Appy Pie may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, to solicit your feedback, or just to keep you updated with what’s going on with Appy Pie and our products. You may also sign up to receive newsletters or other communications from us. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link placed in the emails we send to you, or at your member profile on our website, or by contacting us at       [_privacy@appypie.com_.](mailto:privacy@appypie.com.)

We primarily use our product blogs to communicate this kind of information, so we expect to keep these kinds of emails to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example, via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Appy Pie takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of personal information.

 **Retention of Personal Information**

We will retain your personal information for as long as an Account is active or as needed to provide the Service(s). We will retain Your Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate financial and other records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to terminate your Account or request that we no longer use your personal information, please contact us at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com).

 **Correction or Removal of Personal Information**

Upon request, Appy Pie will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or by contacting us at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Appy Pie acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Appy Pie collects information on behalf of our clients and has no direct relationship with the individuals with whom our clients may interact using the Service(s). If you are a customer of one of our clients (“End-Customer”) and would no longer like to be contacted by that client, please directly contact the client who you interact with. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by service agreements with our Clients. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to Appy Pie’s client (the data controller). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain the personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Clients. We will retain personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

 **Mobile Applications**

When you download, install and use our Mobile Applications, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”).

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure that you receive appropriate notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

We collect your location-based information for the purpose of locating a place that you may be searching for, in your area. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service.

You may opt-out of location-based services at any time by changing the setting at the device level.

We use  **Analytics**  to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Application on your mobile or handheld device. This Mobile Application may record information such as how often you use the Mobile Application, the events that occur within the Mobile Application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the Mobile Application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the Mobile Application.

 **Links to Third Party Sites**

Our Websites contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by Appy Pie. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other such websites or third parties. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Websites and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information.

 **Testimonials**

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Websites, which may contain personal information. Prior to posting the testimonial, we obtain the customer’s consent to post their name along with their testimonial.

 **Tracking Technologies**

Appy Pie and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website.

 **Ads**

We partner with a third party to deliver ads appearing on any of our Websites or Applications to users. Our third-party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [here[3]](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) & if you are located in the European Union (EU) click [here[4].](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) Please note that you will continue to receive generic ads.

 **Analytics**

We collect analytics information when you use Appy Pie’s Websites to help us improve them. Appy Pie may also share data about your actions on our Websites with third-party service providers of analytics services.

 **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com).

 **Changes to The Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

 **Social Media Features**

Appy Pie’s Websites include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button, the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs. After taking your consent, these features may collect your IP address, the page you are visiting on our Websites and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

 **Children’s Personal Information**

Appy Pie doest not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 16. If you are under the age of 16, please do not submit any personal information through our Websites or Apps. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through the Websites or Apps without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 16 has provided personal information to us through the Websites or Services, please contact us at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com), and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information.

 **Contact Us**

If you have questions regarding this Policy or about Appy Pie’s privacy practices, please contact us by email at [privacy@appypie.com](mailto:privacy@appypie.com) or write in to us at Appy Pie LLC, 170 W Shirley Ave #203 B, Warrenton, VA 20186, USA

 **English Version Controls**

Non-English translations of this Policy are provided for convenience only. In the event of any ambiguity or conflict between translations, the English version is authoritative and controls.
